BAPTISTE CANDELLIER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

C	+33 6 41 66 63 55		
\succ	baptiste.candellier@gmail.com		
0	dev.outadoc.fr		
☆	Caen, France		

Bonjour, grüezi! I am a 22-year old French developer currently preparing a software engineering degree.

I would love to work on innovative products outside of France, preferably in Switzerland, starting in September 2018.

I'm particularly interested in working on wearable and mobile products, and love to play around with new tech.

WORK EXPERIENCE

September 2015-August 2018

Caen, France



Software Engineering Apprentice / Natixis

3-year apprenticeship with ENSICAEN. Java and C# .NET development in an Agile team for business applications.

- C# .NET thin desktop clients with Telerik framework
- C# .NET Core REST API development, using multiple DBMSs
- LDAP, FileNet integration
- Test and behaviour-driven development practices
- Continuous integration and deployment with Jenkins and XL Deploy
- git usage with Atlassian tools and gitflow best practices
- Java EE development on IBM AIX using Spring and Spring-Batch
- Agile development on business applications (data processing, invoicing) in a team of ±10 developers
- **UX design** on desktop applications

April 2015-June 2015

Caen, France



Software Development Intern / NXP Semiconductors

Development of a Java EE module for an LDAP directory connection.

- Discovered LDAP, Active Directory and how to integrate it into an application
- Discovered Java EE, Tomcat and basic web server configuration
- Agile development of a module in a small team

PERSONAL PROJECTS

I often work on small personal projects to solve problems I meet every day, mostly for Android (Java, Kotlin) and Python.

2013-Today Twistoast (Android)

An application to keep track of the schedules of the buses and tramways in Caen. Kotlin, SQLite, web scraping, API reverse-engineering, behaviour-driven development

2012-2015 SkinSwitch (Android)

A complete skin manager for Minecraft. **Java**, SQLite, web scraping, API reverse-engineering

→ See more at dev.outadoc.fr and github.com/outadoc

INTERESTS

# technology	# rock	# security
# wearables	# privacy	# design

EDUCATION

2015-Present

Diplôme d'ingénieur

ENSICAEN, Caen, France

Apprenticeship in computer science: specialised in electronic monetary transactions and security.

2013-2015

Diplôme de technicien ES en Informatique

IUT de Caen, Université de Caen, France

2-year Diplôme Universitaire de Technologie in computer science. Databases, C, Java, PHP, economy, communication...

2013

Maturité

Lycée Charles de Gaulle, Caen, France

Baccalauréat scientifique. Majors: mathematics, physics, chemistry, biology.

LANGUAGES

French Native speaker

English Fluent (TOEIC: 990)

Spanish Basic communication skills